翻译：Iz      Tiogy      红豆包      小布拿拿
校对&总监：Iz
后期：斯人     时间轴：深夏桃子
更多动画  就在@欧美动漫汉化军团
开心汉堡店》第五季第十八集
妈妈说总会这样的喷雾剂[日子]
除虫害公司
我的生日
My birthday.
天呐
Boy...
我都不愿提醒自己这件事
I can't even say it to myself.
四十...
Forty-f...
睡过去完事
Maybe I'll sleep through this one.
老妈  醒了吗
Mom! Are you up yet?
我们也许会  也许不会给你惊喜哦
We may or may not have a surprise for you.
我们进来啦
We're coming in!
盖上你的咪咪
Put your boobs away.
抱歉 美女 我们在找我们老妈
Excuse me, young lady, we're looking for our mother,
在她生日这天我们要服侍她在床上吃早餐
to serve her breakfast in bed on her birthday.
是的 我们无意打扰你
Yeah, we don't mean to bother you.
很显然你正在拍画报呢
You're obviously in the middle of a photo shoot,
因为你是位年轻的超级名模
'cause you're a youthful supermodel.
各位 她就是老妈啊
Guys, this is Mom.
什么
What?!
生日快乐 老妈
Happy birthday, Mom!
美味的吐司 鸡蛋  橙汁 还有超美的妈妈
Happy toast, eggs and orange juice, pretty mom!
谢谢你们
Thank you, kids.
真贴心
It's lovely.
我生日最棒的部分
The best part of my birthday
就是我的宝贝们每年都服侍我在床上吃早餐了
is my babies bringing me breakfast in bed every year.
别那么快下结论
Not so fast.
今年也许有新东西哦
There might be more this year.
在蛋白里加一滴金缕梅
Okay, "Add a drop of witch hazel to the egg whites
让皮肤更紧致 更光滑
for even tighter, smoother skin."
如何享受到完美的水疗
没有金缕梅 用醋怎么样
Don't have witch hazel, but how about vinegar?
都差不多 应该可以吧
Same thing. Maybe.
琳达会爱死这惊喜的
Linda is gonna love this.
你说得对  鲍勃
"You're right, Bob.
你是最棒的丈夫
You're the best husband."
谢谢你  醋
Thank you, vinegar.
没有金缕梅是好事儿
I'm glad witch hazel's not here.
吐司有点焦了
Oh, the toast is a little burnt.
没错 就是你喜欢的口感
Yep, just the way you like it.
-还很硬 -又焦又硬
- Oh, and hard. - Burnt and hard.
每年我都问 她为什么喜欢这种口味
Every year I say, "Why does she like it this way?"
但我又会说 就按她喜欢的口味做吧
But then I say, "Hey, make it the way she likes it."
孩子们 我这里需要帮忙
Kids, I could use a little help in here.
但我们想看她啃东西 老爸
But we like to watch her graze, Dad.
去吧  我自己挺好
Go on, I'm good.
也许可以给我带片新的吐司
Maybe bring me some new toast!
搅拌到出泡沫
Stir until frothy.
这得凭主观判断
That's subjective.
孩子们  你们觉得这叫有泡沫了吗
Kids, does this look frothy to you?
我见过更多泡沫的
I've seen frothier.
那是什么 蛋白吗
What is that, egg whites?
差不多  还有醋
Mostly. And vinegar.
-吉恩  能把那黄瓜切一下吗  -没问题
- Gene, would you slice up that cucumber?  - On it.
蒂娜 你能做这个吗
And, Tina, can you do this?
蛋黄酱头发护理
A mayonnaise hair treatment?
我会让老妈的头发像三明治一样闪耀的
Mom's hair is gonna shine like a beautiful sandwich.
为什么自助水疗感觉都很美味
Why is home spa day so delicious?
露易丝  你能打扫一下这儿吗
Oh, Louise, and can you just clean up this mess?
-什么  -你是最小的
- What?!  - You're the youngest.
我也是最不会打扫的  看
I'm also the worst at cleanup. Look.
-吉恩  你切完黄瓜打扫一下 -不要
- Gene, after you're done with the cucumbers, clean up.  - No.
蒂娜  你弄完头发护理
Tina, after you do the hair treatment,
-能打扫一下吗  -好咧
- can you clean up?  - Okay.
我现在能出来了吗
Can I come out now?
还不行 琳
Not yet, Lin!
什么
What?
现在呢
How about now?
还差点
Almost!
现在呢
Now?
还早  抱歉
Not really close at all, sorry.
你昨天买牛奶了吗
Well, did you happen to get milk yesterday?
没有  我忘了
No, I forgot.
我满脑子都是
I was preoccupied with something
这件我认为你会喜欢的事
that I think you're gonna like!
很贴心
That's nice,
但总得有人去买东西呀
but somebody has to do the shopping!
我今天下午去
I'll do it this afternoon!
好吧  我在这里快得幽居病了
Okay, I'm getting a little cabin fever in here.
你们背着我准备惊喜的同时
What if I go to the store and do our shopping
我去商店买东西
while you guys do whatever you're doing
怎么样
that I don't know about?
给我乖乖呆在里面
Stay in there!
别逼我们把你锁起来
Don't make us chain you up!
事实上  这主意非常不错
Actually, that could work out perfectly.
-我们需要更多时间  -你们说啥
- We could use the extra time.  - What?
我去蒙住她眼睛
I'm gonna blindfold her.
往她头上套两个袋子
Double-bag the head.
很好
Doing good.
向左边点
Little to the left.
露易丝
Louise!
我说了往左
I-I said to your left.
我们到了
And we're here.
为什么要蒙住我的眼睛
Why'd I have to be blindfolded?
因为你会偷看
'Cause you're a sneaky peeky.
慢慢逛  琳
Hey, take your time, Lin.
对自己好点
Uh, treat yourself.
去好点的那家超市
Go to the good store.
你是说更远的那家么
You mean the one that's further away?
没错
Yeah!
好点的那家
The good store?
去买最好的那种软糖冰淇淋
Get the premium fudge pops!
没买到你就别想回家
Don't you come home without them!
是啊  为了帮你庆祝生日
Yeah, for your birthday.
没错  生日快乐
Right, happy birthday!
一会儿见
See you when you get back!
-再见  -对了  能再买点蛋黄酱吗
- Bye. - Oh, and can you get more mayonnaise?
家里的用完了  但我今天得用
We're out and I need it today.
和惊喜无关
But not for a surprise.
纯属我个人需要
Just, um, 'cause I need it.
-好吧  蒂娜 -多谢
-Okay, Tina. - Thank you.
再见
Good-bye.
很好  金泽  很好  像以前一样
It was nice, Ginger. It was nice, as always.
但他们鼓弄东西的时候
But then they wanted me to stay in my room forever
老想让我待在房间里
while they set something else up.
我都快待疯了
I was going crazy in there!
而且  还没人去采购东西
Meanwhile, no one did the shopping,
只好我去了
so that's what I'm doing.
粉笔画展
Chalk festival.
下一次是什么 蜡笔大会吗
What's next, a crayon convention?
铅笔游行吗
A pencil parade? Right?
不管怎样  我知道我的家人都是好意
Anyway, I know my family means well,
但我真希望能告诉他们我讨厌生日
but I wish I could just tell them I hate my birthday.
人一上年纪生日就没什么乐趣了
You get to a certain age and they're no fun.
我二十岁时  很拉轰的
In my 20s, I had va va voom,
现在不行了
now I just have va va.
他们这样服侍我在床上吃早餐
And it feels like breakfast in bed is just practice now
感觉像是为我以后去养老院做准备  有没有
for when they put me in a home, right?
不管怎样  多谢听我发泄  金泽
Well, anyway, thanks for letting me vent, Ginger.
抱歉录了这么长的留言
Sorry for the long voice mail.
有空电我
Call me when you can.
爱你 孩子  再见
Love you, kid. Bye.
好像永远也排不到头
This is taking forever.
我这里可以帮三号柜台排在最前面人结账
I can help whoever's next on check stand three!
太好了
Oh, great.
-多谢  -抱歉
- Thank you. - Uh, hey, excuse me!
他说排在最前面的  应该是我
He said whoever's next. That's me.
我排在最前面
I'm next in line.
你在我后面  记得吗
You were behind me, 'member?
-你刚刚在那边  -没关系
- You were just over there... - Oh, it's okay.
我只有几样东西
I only have a few things.
这个和那个  还有那个
This and that and this other thing.
几样东西  她买了一车的果汁好吗
A few things? She's got a cart full of juice.
-迪得莉  最近好吗  -你好
- Deirdre! How's it going? - Hi!
天呐  他们认识
Oh, my God, they know each other.
这些都是为小镇粉笔画展买的吗
Is all of this for "Chalk of the Town"?
是的  我们希望今年有更多人参加
Yeah, we're hoping for a bigger turnout this year.
那愚蠢的粉笔画展
That stupid chalk festival.
但我不确定这杯子如何
I'm not sure about these cups though.
想得好
Good instinct.
既然你提了
Since you brought it up,
这些杯子的确不怎么样
these are not the good cups.
什么
What?
快和我说说
Tell me everything.
这些会漏  真不知道为什么还卖它们
They leak. I don't know why I even sell them.
我们有卖更好的杯子  价格一样
We have better cups for the same price.
很讽刺  它们在架子底部
The ones on the bottom shelf, ironically.
很显然 我得去拿那些杯子
Well, clearly I got to have those cups.
去拿吧  我等你
Go get them. I'll wait for you.
谢谢你
Oh, thanks.
-我三点下班  对我没差  -难以置信
- I'm here til l3:00, I don't care. - Unbelievable.
最好再拿点冰
Oh, and you might want to grab some more ice, too.
-那杯子可是"热"卖商品哦  -好主意
- It's a hot one. - Good idea!
她一会儿就好  你不介意的吧
She'll just be a second. You don't mind, right?
很好  多谢
Great, thanks.
先别急
So, you're not done yet.
看看收银条
Let's take a look at this receipt,
你今天省了多少呢
see how much you saved today.
天  对我
Oh, gosh, yes.
我去  够了没
Oh, my God, please!
赶紧的
Just end this!
头发都等白了
We're not getting any younger over here!
那可不能怪我们哟
Well, don't blame us for that.
再次感谢你的杯子小情报
Anyway, thanks again for the tip on the cups.
不客气  记得给我反馈哦
Hey, no problem. Let me know how they work out.
很高兴...和你聊天
Nice, uh, chalking with you.
我也是
You!
终于走了
Finally!
你确定你俩聊完了吗
You sure you guys are done?
等一下  我把这些杯子放回去
Hold on. I have to put these old cups back.
倒霉生日
Stupid birthday.
我讨厌杯子
I hate cups.
我去
Nuts!
向莫特店里借枯掉的花瓣  搞定
Old flower petals from Mort's? Check.
很好  蒂娜  我们要把它撒在
That's great, Tina. We'll spread them
从前门到洗手间浴缸的路上
from the front door into the bathroom to the tub.
就这些
Yeah.
貌似只有...六片啊
That's, like, six... six petals.
看来这个月没办什么葬礼
Yeah, not a lot of funerals this month.
莫特让我节假日再去看看
Mort said to check back around the holidays.
要不就在玄关放一片  门口放一片
Maybe just one in the hallway, one in the doorway,
-然后浴缸再放一片  -对
- and then one at the tub? - Yeah.
我们可以去捡点树枝
Well, we could get some branches.
那效果会一样吗
I'm not sure that will have the same impact.
就让它们都漂在浴缸里吧
Okay, well, just float those in the tub.
应该也很梦幻
That'll still be nice.
我这儿还有新世纪放松身心CD
And here's my New Age relaxation CD.
一个办车库甩卖的女人执意要给我的
A lady having a garage sale forced me to take it.
应该很让人放松吧  我想
That's pretty relaxing, I guess.
那...那是鲸鱼的叫声么
Is... is that whales?
应该是...世上最可怜的鲸鱼吧
I think it's... the saddest whale.
也没那么糟嘛  孩子们
This isn't that bad, you guys.
我们也许真的能把这办好呢
I think we may have actually pulled this together.
我了解你们老妈
I mean, I know your mom,
她肯定会喜欢的
and she's really gonna like this.
这可能会是一次很不错的生日哦
This could end up being a pretty decent birthday.
不错
Pretty decent birthday?
应该是最完美的生日吧
More like best birthday!
最完美的生日
Best birthday?
是她人生最完美的一天吧
Best day of her life!
有完没完
Oh, come on!
口香糖
Gum?
该死  哎呀
Damn it! Wha... oh!
不不不不不
No, no, no, no, no, no!
我讨厌生日
I hate my birthday!
嗨  又是我
Hi. Me again.
我把钥匙锁在车里了  能不能
I locked my keys in my car and I was wondering
借你的电话打给我老公
if I could use your phone to call my husband.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我们的电话是员工专用的
Our phone is for employees only.
可这是紧急情况啊
It's an emergency!
把钥匙锁车里
Locking your keys in your car
-算哪门子紧急情况  -什么
- is not an emergency. - What?
你能去医院告诉医生
You can't check into a hospital
你把钥匙锁车里了他会给你治病么
with a bad case of "You locked your keys in your car."
得  算你狠
You know what? Fine.
我借别人的打
I'll ask to borrow someone's cell phone.
请不要骚扰我们的客人
No harassing our customers.
你知道你的裤子裂缝了吗
Did you know your pants are ripped?
知道
Yes!
不好意思先生  能借你的电话用一下吗
Excuse me, sir, can I borrow your cell phone?
我把钥匙锁车里了
I locked my keys in my car,
我需要打给我老公
and I got to call my husband.
我...没有电话
I don't, have a cell phone.
你没电话
You don't?
那那里面是什么  那是什么
What's that right there? What's that?
我不知道  我要走了
I don't know. I got to go.
等等  等等  回来
Wait, wait, wait, wait, come back!
我是好人
I'm a good person!
你们老妈不接电话
Your mom's not picking up her phone.
我问问你们盖尔姨妈
Let me try Aunt Gayle.
嗨  盖尔  我是鲍勃
Hi, Gayle, it's Bob.
今天琳达有联系你吗
Have you heard from Linda today?
我知道今天是她生日  盖尔
Yes, I know it's her birthday, Gayle.
我只是找不到她人了
I just don't know where she is.
别激动  盖尔  她  她不会有事的
Calm down, Gayle. I-I'm sure she's fine.
盖尔  冷静...
Gayle, pull yourself...
盖尔  盖尔  盖尔
Gayle. Gayle! Gayle!
天呐  她回来了
Oh, my God, there she is.
嗨  琳达
Hi, Linda.
盖尔  她刚回屋了
Gayle, she just walked in.
她没事  她很好
She's fine, she looks great.
再联系  拜
Call you back later. Bye.
你知道老妈并没有回来吧
You know Mom's not really here, right?
我知道  蒂娜
Yes, Tina.
但你说...你看到她了
Because you said she was... you saw her.
我知道  我那是...算了
I know, but I was... Forget it.
-你是在撒谎吗  -好吧  是的
- Were you lying? - All right. Yes.
听我说  你们老妈可能只是车没油了
Listen, your mom probably just ran out of gas or something.
我打给泰迪
I'll call Teddy and see
让他们载我们去超市
if he can drive us out to the store.
和泰迪去超市么
Going to the store with Teddy?
这是要给我们过生日啊
Happy birthday to us.
-嗨  -嗨
- Hi. - Hi.
我知道我看起来有点奇怪
I know I look a little crazy,
但我今天实在很倒霉
but I'm having a rough day.
今天是我生日...
It's my birthday...
-生日快乐  -但我去超市的时候
- Happy birthday! - ...and I locked my keys
把钥匙和电话锁车里了
and my cell phone in my car at the grocery store.
-太糟了  -对
- The worst. - Yeah.
现在我只想回家
And I'm just trying to get home.
这车是去码头的吗
Does this bus go to the wharf?
你交好运啦  是去码头的
You're in luck, yes!
拜托载我一程吧
Oh! Please take me.
我发誓等我到家以后
I swear I will pay you the fare
会付你车费的  拜托了
once I get it from my apartment. Please.
没问题  上来吧
Okay. Come on up.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
太感谢了
Thank you!
总算有件好事了
Finally, something's going right.
我不会放你鸽子的
You won't regret this.
等等  等等  你这是去哪儿
Wait, wait, wait, where you going?
码头在那边啊
The wharf is the other way!
这是去原始丛林码头的快速公交啊
This is the express to Wildwood Wharf.
不然你以为是什么码头
What wharf did you think?
奇幻码头啊  我不是往那边指了吗
Wonder Wharf! The one I was pointing at!
我还以为你不擅长指方向呢
I just thought you were a bad pointer.
停车让我下去
Pull over so I can get off.
我没法停  这是在高速上
I can't pull over; We're on the highway.
得等到下一站才能停
You'll have to wait until we get to our next stop.
老天爷
Oh, my God.
那我一会儿下车
Well, I guess I'll just get on the next bus
去坐下一班反方向的公车就行了  对吧
going the other way, right?
那就是我回程的车
That'd be me on my way back. Oh!
不到一个半小时
Shouldn't be more than an hour and a half.
我看你还是坐车上得了
Might as well just stay on.
我们可以来玩字母游戏
Hey, we can play the alphabet game!
一个半小时
An hour and a half?
我还是走回去吧
Oh. I'll just walk back.
行  那我们在到下一站之前玩吧
Fine, we'll play till the next stop.
那的路标上有个A
There's an "A" On that sign.
我领先了哦  那有个B
I'm winning. There's a "B."
你落后了哦  我已经得两分了
You're falling behind! I got two!
肯定很好玩
It's gonna be fun.
可惜那些软糖冰淇淋了
Those poor fudge pops.
肯定得化掉了
They don't stand a chance.
但是可以再冻起来啊  对吗  对吧
They'll refreeze though, right? Right?!
当然可以  当形状会变得很奇怪
Sure they will, but they'll be in weird shapes.
-超级奇怪  -没错
- Super weird. - Yeah.
你去哪儿了  老妈
Where are you, Mom?!
她没在店里
Okay, she's not in the store,
但她肯定去过
but she definitely was.
收银员不怎么喜欢她
The checker did not like her.
-很明显  -你怎么看出来的
- That was clear. - How could you tell?
-很明显  -什么意思
- It was clear. - What do you mean?
他自己说的  说他讨厌她
He said so. He hated her.
他说他讨厌  "我讨厌...
He said he hate... "I hated..."
"你老婆"
"...your wife."
但他也表示她应该是走着离开了
But he did say he thinks she took off walking.
但我们开车来的路上没看见她
And we didn't see her on the drive here,
那她肯定是往反方向走的
so she must have walked in a different way?
我们永远找不到她了
We'll never find her!
有好多条回家的路
There are dozens of ways to walk home!
还有好多在街上走路的妇女
And dozens of women walking!
我们怎么知道哪个是她
How will we know which one is her?
我都已经开始忘记她长什么样了
I'm already forgetting what she looks like.
-她是个女的  -我记得她...挺高的
- She's a woman. - I think she's... tall.
她戴眼镜吗
Does she have glasses?
我记不得了
I can't remember.
对的  她戴
Yes! Yes, she does.
好了  集中注意力  好吗
All right, let's focus, okay?
她有个钩子手  我确定
She has a hook for a hand! I'm sure of it!
吉恩  别闹
Gene, no.
好吧  我要是走回去
Okay, so if I'm gonna walk it,
是从那边穿过去吗
I could cut through that way?
你在指着我
You're pointing at me.
你跟谁学的指方向
Where did you learn to point?
不  我指的你背后
No, I'm pointing through you.
-但你手指对着我  -我指的那边的...
- But it's at me. - The other side of the...
我后面吗
Oh, behind me?
这样就明白了
Well, that makes a lot more sense.
对的  你得从那儿走
Yeah, no, that's where you want to walk.
好的  谢了  安德鲁
Okay, thanks, Andrew.
拜拜  琳达
Bye, Linda.
-拜拜  -好的  拜拜  琳达
- Bye. - Okay, bye, Linda.
生日快乐  哔哔
Happy birthday. Beep-beep.
是我学的  喇叭坏了
That's me. The horn doesn't work.
拜拜
Bye.
好吧  你妈只可能走这条路
Well, this is the only other street your mom could've taken.
-她到底去哪儿了  -我们得快点找到她
- Where is she? - We got to find her.
我们多不在她身边一秒
Every minute we're not with her,
她的生日就糟糕一分
she's having a worse and worse birthday.
她肯定停哪了  但她能去哪呢
She must have stopped somewhere, but where would she go?
夏卡・康来城里了吗[美国女演员]
Is Chaka Khan in town?
没有  她要12月才来
Nope, she doesn't come through till December.
老妈有可能是饿了
Mom probably got hungry.
她15分钟就要进食一次
She needs to eat every 15 minutes
不然会变身魔鬼
or she becomes a monster.
但她没有钱
But she doesn't have any money.
她把钱包锁车里了
She locked her purse in the car.
邓芬多芙面包店
Oh, Devendorf's Bakery.
他们试吃小样给的很多
They're really generous with their samples.
老妈和我以前经常去
Mom and I go there a lot.
-是么  -其实好久没去了
- You do? - Well, it's actually been a while.
我俩都很担心泳衣季
We're both worried about bathing suit season.
值得一试
I guess it's worth a try.
去邓芬多芙面包店
To Devendorf's Bakery!
去试吃啦
To free samples!
烂泥
Mud.
好了  琳达
Okay, Linda.
想想好的一面
Try to look on the bright side.
你平时哪有机会像这样在田野间散步呢
How often do you get to walk through a field?
多棒呀  看看周围
It's kind of neat. Look around.
多好的天
It's a nice day.
还有美丽的小花
Oh, here's a pretty flower.
天呐  是只臭鼬
Oh, God,it's skunk.
他在睡觉
Oh, he's sleeping.
悄悄走开不打扰你
Just gonna tiptoe away and not bother you.
天啊
Oh, God!
我的脸
Oh, my face!
天呐  讨厌的臭鼬
Oh, God, that stupid skunk!
夜行蠢货[臭鼬多在夜间活动]
Nocturnal idiot!
看在上帝的份上
Oh, for the love of Pete!
还有一边能看得见
I can still see out of one side.
那黑毛东西是什么
Sort of. What's that black fuzzy thing?
你这小臭鼬
Oh, you little skunk!
这就是你和老妈来的地方吗
So this is where you go with your mom, huh?
让我来说
Yeah, now let me do the talking.
你装萌就好
You just look cute.
你好  好久不见
Hey, you, long time no see.
今天的黑麦面包怎么样
How's the pumpernickel today?
干吗  我试试这小样
Dry? Better try a sample.
你好  我在找我的老婆
Hello, uh, I'm looking for my wife.
她是黑头发戴红眼睛
She's got black hair and red glasses.
不得了的手腕和巨大的手掌
And amazing wrists, but huge hands.
-泰迪  怎么了  -我只想具体点
- Teddy. What? - I'm just trying to be specific.
你是说她妈
You mean her?
是啊  等等  你怎么有她的...
Yes. Wait, why do you have a photo of...
等下  那照片写了什么
Wait, what does that say on the picture?
写着"别给她吃"
It says "Do not feed."
-什么  -别给她吃
- What? - Do not feed.
你老婆在滥用我们的试吃宣传策略
Your wife was abusing our free sample policy.
我们贴了照片后她就没来过了
She hasn't been in here since we posted the photo.
她还不带我自己来过吗
She's been coming here without me?
那男的怎么了
What did that guy do?
他想要我们把面包壳切掉
He wants his crusts cut off.
她呢
What did she do?
她什么都摸  什么都摸
She touches everything. Everything.
他又干什么了
What did he do?
他种族歧视
He's really racist.
那小宝宝怎么了
What did that baby do?
他是个熊孩子  好吧
He's just a jerk. Okay, fine.
多谢  我们要走了
Thank you. Uh, we're leaving.
孩子们  走吧
Kids, let's go.
既然你要给试吃小样
You know, maybe don't give out free samples
也许就不该看不惯那些来试吃的人
and then get mad at people when they eat them.
你知道吗  其实
Well, you know, unfortunately,
我们每天烤的所有面包
we can't bake enough in a day
都塞不满你老婆的巨掌
to fill your wife's giant hands.
这世上只有那么多黑麦面包
There's only so much pumpernickel in the world.
你说什么
What did you say?
你这蠢货面包师
You poor dumb baker.
等着受死吧
Here comes the thunder.
你知道吗  我绝不准人嘲笑...
Guess what? No one talks about...
我老婆的巨掌
My wife's giant hands...
-淡定淡定  -尤其在她生日这天
- Easy. - On her birthday!
泰迪例外  因为
Except for Teddy, because...
-好吧  -他还
- All right... - he also...
夸了  她的手腕
complimented... her wrists!
还有  这黑麦面包确实太干了
And this pumpernickel is dry!
还有点脏
And a little dirty.
请带我一程
Please give me a ride!
-我把钥匙锁在车  -天呐  快走  走
- I locked my keys in my car... - Oh, God, go, go!
又上错了车  今天还是我生日
And I got on the wrong bus and it's my birthday!
好吧  我们再想想
All right, let's all think.
你们老妈在超市
Where else could your mom have possibly gone
和家之间还能去哪
between the grocery store and home?
好的好的  我是老妈
Okay, okay, I'm Mom.
我在到处逛  唱着歌
I'm walking around, I'm singing.
她去大便了
She stopped to poop!
对哦  我怎么没想到
Of course! Why didn't I think of that?
我们应该去看看
We should check the bathroom in the lobby
皇家珍珠酒店大堂的厕所
of the Royal Oyster Hotel.
-为什么是那个  -那是老妈的最爱
- Why that one? - It's Mom's favorite.
-什么  -那老妈每次说的
- What? - So that's what Mom means
去剥个珍珠就是去那儿喽
when she says she's going to shuck an oyster.
天呐
Oh, my God.
我想去看看这厕所
I want to see this bathroom.
我可以去
I could go.
我们去皇家珍珠酒店吧
Let's go to the Royal Oyster Hotel.
我们需要事先打电话告知酒店
Should we call ahead to let them know
我们都要去大便吗
we'll all be pooping?
好像你们闻起来很香似的
Oh, like you guys smell so good.
原来只是小便
Turns out it was just number one.
多谢  泰迪
Thank you, Teddy.
我可不一样  我来了个大满贯
Not for me. I hit a grand slam.
干得好  吉恩
Really good job, Gene.
-多谢  -老妈不在
- Thank you. - No Mom.
但他们换了新的香薰
But they did get a new potpourri.
老妈会爱死的
Mom's gonna love it.
打扰一下  你们是酒店的客人吗
Excuse me, are you guests of the hotel?
不  我们  我们是
No, uh, we're, uh, we're...
我们在找我的老婆
We're just looking for my wife.
她有时候会来这
She sometimes comes here to...
用洗手间
use the... restroom.
琳达吗
Oh, Linda?
你肯定是鲍勃
You must be Bob!
是的  等等  你认识她吗
Yes. Wait, y-you know her?
是的  一个女的隔三差五
Well, as much as you can know a woman
来你酒店大便  能不认识吗
who comes to your hotel once or twice a week to poop.
今天不是她生日吗
Hey, isn't it her birthday today?
是的
Uh, yes.
蒂姆  你今天看到琳达了吗
Hey, Tim. Have you seen Linda today?
拜托  现在还没到中午
Oh, please, it's barely noon.
*她下午才大便*
*She does her B.M. In the P.M.*
你好  蒂姆
Hi, Tim.
*你好  蒂娜*
*Hey, Tina *
*姑娘  最近如何*
*How you doing, girl?*
好吧  她不在这  我们还是走吧
Huh, well, she's not here, so we better go.
什么  不  再待会吧
What? No, stay a little.
这么多年终于见到真人了
We finally get to meet you after all these years.
-这么多年  -时间都去哪儿了
- Years? - Where does the time go?
我  我们真的得去找我妻子了
We-we really got to find my wife.
不过很高兴见到你
Nice meeting you though.
-拜  -拜
- Bye. - Bye.
帮我向琳达问好
Say hi to Linda for me.
转告她我们厕所买新的香薰了
Tell her we got new potpourri.
她说得对极了
She was absolutely right.
我会的
Will do.
再  走  四条街
Just four more blocks.
我去  又是这玩意儿
Oh, God, this thing?
欢迎参加小镇粉笔画展
Welcome to Chalk of the Town.
天  又是你
Oh, God, it's you.
是你和你那烂纸杯啊
Oh, you and your dumb cups.
你这是咋了
What happened?
这味儿
Oh, you smell.
我这一上午很坎坷  迪得莉
It's been a rough morning, Deirdre.
你穿的那啥  外穿尿布么
What is that, some sort of street diaper?
你才是外穿尿布
You're a street diaper.
-你才是外穿尿布  -你才是
- No, you're the street diaper. - No, you!
穿着外穿尿布的人是你好吗
Okay, you're the one actually wearing a street diaper,
所以如果真有谁是外穿尿布的话  肯定是你
so if anyone is a street diaper, it's you.
一边儿去  外穿尿布  我要过去了
Step aside, street diaper. I'm going through.
抱歉  没票可不行
Oh, not without a ticket, I'm afraid.
抱歉  这是公共街道
Well, I'm afraid it's a public street,
别给我挡道
so get out of my way.
你要是在超市态度好点
You should have been nicer at the grocery store
我还可以考虑一下
and maybe I would.
哎哟  你的纸杯洒了
Your cups are spilling!
你在做...天呐
What are you do... Oh, my God.
看来杯子质量也不咋地嘛
I guess these weren't the good ones after all.
别过去
Oh, don't!
站住  不
Stop! No!
我的粉笔画
My chalksterpiece!
给我一点别动
Do not move.
慢慢走出来
Just carefully step off.
这是啥玩意儿
What is this?
美国故事
It's the story of America,
你把它给磨花了  老太婆
and you're scuffing it up, you hag!
老太婆
Hag?!
-怎样  -听好了
- Yep. - You know what I think?
我觉得我该来点滑步
I think I'm gonna do a little twist.
-别  别  -一个滑步一声叫
- No. No. - A little twist and shout.
-不  你敢  -边滑边闹
- No! Don't you do it. - A twist a twisty shout.
再来点查尔斯顿舞如何
How-how about the Charleston?
等着我在你脸上跳舞吧
I'm gonna Charleston on your face!
给我回来  我一定要抓到你
Come back here! I'm gonna get you!
救命啊
Help!
-她疯了  - 回来
- She's crazy! - Get back here!
她在破坏艺术
She's destroying the art!
我没有  一直在踩画的人是你
No, I'm not! You're the one stepping all over everything!
抱歉  抱歉
Sorry, sorry!
井盖画得不错
Ooh, good manhole!
太空啊
Ooh, space!
嗨  外星人
Hi, aliens!
该死
Damn it!
大家对你们老妈的看法还真是两极化啊
People are very divided on your mom.
她到底上哪儿去了
Where is she?
我们小镇有教派吗
Does this town have cults?
她搞不好加入了呢
Maybe she joined one of those.
我知道个她可能会去的地方
I might know a place where she could be.
-什么地方  -不过也许不在那儿
- Where? - She's probably not there.
当我没说
I shouldn't have said anything.
咱千万别去
Let's definitely not go.
好吧  她不在这儿  我们走吧
Well, she's not here. Let's call it.
露易丝  等下  你和你妈来过这地方
Wait, Louise, you and your mom come here?
曾经来过
Used to come.
来摸小狗么
To pet the puppies?
才不是  老妈也许是吧
No. I guess.
我不知道  因为我都从没进来过
I don't know; I've never even come inside the store.
我一般都在外面  扔硬币
I'm always outside just pitching pennies,
摔瓶子  你懂的  当个小流氓
breaking bottles, you know, being a hoodlum.
嘿  露易丝  我就猜到时你
Hey, Louise, I thought that was you.
嗨  罗伯特
Oh, hi, Robert.
要我帮你把毛毛上校抱出来吗
Want me to get out Colonel Fluffles again?
他可想你了
He missed you.
嗨  露易丝  你还好吗
Hi, Louise, how you doing?
我去  别看他眼睛
Oh, God, don't make eye contact.
他要把我吸进去了
He's reeling me in.
毛毛上校
Colonel Fluffles!
你太...
You're so...
*有人和老妈来宠物店摸宠物*
*Someone comes to the pet store with Mom.*
我开始觉得我和老妈的蹭厕所之旅
I'm beginning to think my secret bathroom trips with Mom
跟你们的一比简直弱爆了
aren't as fun as what you guys do.
他长大了
he's getting old.
我只是只小狗
I'm just a puppy.
他这次的眼神不怎么亮啊
Well, he's got cloudy eyes this time.
我知道  他眼睛有点...
Yeah, I know, his eyes are a little...
我没事  别担心
But I'm fine. Don't worry about me.
我可是个斗士
I'm a scrapper.
他好像比以前更肉了呀
Oh, he looks lumpier than last time.
我是有点肉
I'm a little bit lumpy,
但这样更可爱嘛
but that's just more to love.
真的是呢
Yes, that is.
要不要和羽毛叔叔打声招呼
Want to say hi to Uncle Feathers?
好的
All right!
它刚刚是说"好的"吗
Did it just say "All right"?
好的
All right!
你们老妈背着我
Your mom leads a rich,
还真是过着丰富又诡异的人生呢
kind of odd life that I did not know about.
鲍鲍  这只鹦鹉有没有让我看起来很酷
Bobby, does this parrot make me look cool?
糟糕  我突然发现
Oh, crap. I just realized,
要是琳达回家了  她会进不了屋
if Linda gets home, she can't get in.
她把钥匙落车里了
She doesn't have her keys.
我们应该留一个人在家的
One of us should have stayed behind.
-我不要  -已经晚了  吉恩
- Not it. - Gene, it's too late.
算  算了  我们走吧
N-Never mind. Let's go.
我做到了  我真的回家了
I did it! I actually made it home.
鲍勃  孩子们
Bob! Kids!
让我进去
Let me in!
妈咪回来了
Mommy's home!
寿星回来啦
It's the birthday girl!
他们都去哪儿了
Where are they?
绝不会让这生日厄运得逞
Not gonna let this birthday win.
欧耶  我赢了
Yes! I win!
妈的
Son of a bitch.
-老妈  -琳
- Mom? - Lin?
水疗日快乐
Happy Spa Day.
送给我的
That's me.
你确定你只遇到一只臭鼬么  老妈
You sure it was only one skunk, Mom?
不  两只  也可能一只遇到两次
No, it was two, or it was the same guy twice.
老妈  我能把我的奶酪三明治
Mom, is it cool if I dip my grilled cheese
-在你的番茄浴池里蘸一下吗  -蘸吧
- in your tomato bath? - Yeah, go ahead.
等等  所以你说那马是啥颜色来着
Yeah! So, wait, what color were the horses again?
-纯棕色  好像是  -太棒了
- Just plain brown, I guess. - Yes.
琳  我有话要告诉你
Lin, I got to tell you,
我今天认识了全新的你
I learned some new things about you today.
我以前没见过的你
Stuff I didn't know.
我更加尊敬的你  某种程度上
Stuff I respect, kind of,
我很高兴  结婚这么多年
and I'm glad to say, after all these years,
我还能发现这样的小惊喜
I'm still finding little surprises.
还有就是  我把这些话都写在生日贺卡上了
Also, I wrote all of that in your birthday card.
-看  -真的呢
- See? - Oh, yeah.
是的  都是我写的
Yep, I did that.
不过  抱歉你的生日搞砸了  琳
But sorry your birthday was horrible, Lin.
别道歉啊
Hey, don't be sorry.
-这是我过过的最棒的生日  -啥
- This was the best birthday ever. - What?
真的  我扇了今天一记狠狠的耳光
Yeah. I kicked this day's butt.
看来我还是不减当年啊
I still got it.
没准我比以前更厉害了呢
I think I might even be getting better.
我想让它成为一项新传统
I want this to be the new tradition.
我之后每年的生日
Every year on my birthday,
你们都蒙上我的眼  随便把我送到什么地方
you blindfold me and you drop me off somewhere
不给我手机和钱
with no cell phone and no money,
-让我自己找回家  -就这么说定了
- and I have to make my way home. - Deal!
现在可以加血腥玛丽了
Now let's Bloody Mary up this tub!
今天可是老妈的生日
It's Mommy's birthday!
-吉恩  去拿伏特加  -好咧
- Gene, grab the vodka! All right. - On it!
*午后上大号*
*B.M. In the P.M. *
*她在午后上大号*
*She does a B.M. In the P.M. *
*不是小号  是大号*
*Not number one, number two*
*这是为你我准备的香薰*
*It's a potpourri for you and me, yeah*
*她在午后上大号*
*She does a B.M. In the P.M. *
*你得*
*You gotta*
-*当她想上大号*  -*在午后上大号*
- *When she gotta go, yeah* - *B.M. In the p.M. *
*就得上大号*
*She gotta go, yeah,
*当她想上大号*
*when she gotta go, yeah*
*就得上大号*
*She gotta go, yeah *
*因为当她想上大号  她就得去上*
*'Cause when she gotta go, she gotta go *
*她去大便*
*She does a B.M. *